<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog | Abakar Gasanov</title>
    <link>https://vigestry.github.io/en/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://vigestry.github.io/en/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://vigestry.github.io/media/icon_hu_645fa481986063ef.png</url>
      <title>Blog</title>
      <link>https://vigestry.github.io/en/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inspiration and New Plans</title>
      <link>https://vigestry.github.io/en/post/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vigestry.github.io/en/post/05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-week-from-july-23-to-july-29&#34;&gt;📌 Week from July 23 to July 29&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The holidays are gradually reaching their midpoint, and I felt the urge to engage in something more productive.&lt;br&gt;
I started working on a small project in Python for practice: planning to build a simple personal expense tracking app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, I created a reading list and study materials to prepare for the next semester.&lt;br&gt;
It feels like summer is becoming not only a time for rest but also a launchpad for future ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Sports and Active Leisure</title>
      <link>https://vigestry.github.io/en/post/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vigestry.github.io/en/post/04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-week-from-july-16-to-july-22&#34;&gt;📌 Week from July 16 to July 22&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week was all about sports. Together with friends, I took part in an amateur football tournament, and although we didn’t take first place, the emotions were unforgettable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also tried myself at table tennis and realized that it’s a great way to distract from everyday tasks.&lt;br&gt;
The holidays are turning into a time not only for relaxation but also for strengthening health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Impressions from Summer Walks</title>
      <link>https://vigestry.github.io/en/post/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vigestry.github.io/en/post/03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-week-from-july-9-to-july-15&#34;&gt;📌 Week from July 9 to July 15&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week was eventful: together with classmates, we walked around Moscow and discovered many new and interesting places.&lt;br&gt;
We visited several museums, which inspired reflections on how technology influences culture and education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alongside the walks, I continued reading literature on business informatics — it turned out that many books provide a practical perspective on what will be studied in senior courses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long-Awaited Holidays — Time to Rest</title>
      <link>https://vigestry.github.io/en/post/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vigestry.github.io/en/post/02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-week-from-july-2-to-july-8&#34;&gt;📌 Week from July 2 to July 8&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exams are behind me, and the holidays have finally begun! The first feeling is lightness and joy.&lt;br&gt;
I dedicated this week to rest: spent more time with friends, played football, and finally managed to read books peacefully without thinking about exams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also enrolled in several online courses for self-development to keep up the learning rhythm during the summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exams — the First Serious Challenge</title>
      <link>https://vigestry.github.io/en/post/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vigestry.github.io/en/post/01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-week-from-june-25-to-july-1&#34;&gt;📌 Week from June 25 to July 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main topic of this week was the exam session. The atmosphere was tense but exciting: for the first time, I had to take several serious exams in a row.&lt;br&gt;
What stood out the most was preparing for the mathematics exam — I had to review my notes and solve dozens of problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Business Informatics exam turned out to be less difficult than expected: most questions focused on theory and examples of real-world applications in companies.&lt;br&gt;
It really feels like the first year of studies is reaching an important milestone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
